■
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：红豆包    IZ    奈奈良    糯
■
校对：糯      时间轴：今
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第三集
后期：森    总监：萌
■
吉恩  你在干嘛
Gene, what are you doing?
晒黑皮肤  夏天已经过半
Tanning! It's the middle of summer
我看起来还像一个英国贵妇
and I look like a British lady.
《查理与巧克力工厂》里
橙肤绿毛的小矮人
悠着点  乔治・汉密尔顿
Hey, slow it down, George Hamilton.
难道你想变成小矮人吗
You want to look like an Oompa Loompa?
吉恩  你要是想弄黑皮肤
Gene, if you want a tan,
不如穿上汉堡服出去晒晒  顺便发下试吃品
why don't you go out in the burger suit for a while and hand out samples?
没门  我才不想晒出汉堡形呢
No way. I don't want burger lines.
鲍勃・贝尔彻  你的包裹
Package for Bob Belcher.
-老爸  叫你呢  -谢了  吉恩
- Dad, that's you! - Thanks, Gene.
一个神秘的包裹  里面会是什么呢
A mystery package! What could it be?
寄件地址是我老爸以前的餐馆
Huh, the return address is my dad's old restaurant.
真奇怪
That's weird.
有张纸条
There's a note.
是那些买下你老爸餐馆的女士寄来的
It's from those ladies who bought your dad's place.
亲爱的鲍勃  这个盒子是
Dear Bob, the workmen found this box
工人们在整修排气孔时发现的
when they were redoing the air vents.
我们担心里面有震动装置
We were afraid it had vibrators in it.
天哪  可算放心了
Boy, were we relieved.
仔细想想  任何盒子里面都可能有震动装置
If you think about it, any box could have vibrators in it.
天哪  是我的玩具
Oh, my God, it's my toys!
这些在我小的时候就不见了
Wow, I haven't seen these since I was just a kid.
以前我总是偷偷藏着它们
I used to hide it from my dad
因为老爸不让我在工作时玩玩具
because he didn't want me to have toys during work hours.
你被耍了  老爸
Joke's on you, dad.
你的玩具箱被人塞满了垃圾
Someone filled your toy box with trash.
什么  不
What? No.
这是我的朋友  布瑞里
This is my friend, Brilly.
一块清洁布
A scouring pad?
是清洁好帮手
A scouring pal.
还有我的二战战斗机
And my World War II fighter plane.
还有我的小狗  道格拉维奇先生
And my dog, Mr. Doglavich.
-那是肥皂  -没错  可是你看
- That's soap. - Yeah, but see?
这形状很像小狗吧
It's sort of shaped like a dog.
这是一种什么心情
What is this feeling I'm feeling right now?
我在替别人感到难过吗
It's like I'm sad for another person?
是这样吗  我疯了吗
Is that a thing? Am I going crazy?!
听着  我们成长的年代不同
Look, times were different when I was growing up.
玩的东西也就不同
We had to make our own fun.
来  拿着玩玩  你们会明白的
Here, try these. You'll see.
明白了吧
See?
现在我明白了
Now I get it.
要说好玩的话  这东西可真是太好玩了
If anything, this is too fun.
我想摸摸这只狗
I want to pet the dog!
不  道格拉维奇先生
No, Mr. Doglavich!
-抱歉  老爸  -他死了
- Sorry, dad. - He's dead.
你可以带他去肥皂诊所
You could take him to the soap vet.
不  不行  蒂娜
No, I can't, Tina!
我们要把他埋在后院
We're going to bury him out back.
大家穿好外套
Everybody get your coats.
-鲍勃  别闹了  -不
- Bob, stop it now. - No!
现在是夏天
It's summer!
我的狗  死掉了
That's my dog! He's dead!
去休息休息
Go take a time-out.
我要写一首悼词
I'm gonna write a eulogy.
与君相识如此短暂  你这只死翘翘的肥皂狗
I knew you so briefly, you dead soap dog.
我想我能让他恢复原状
Oh! I think I can fix him.
好了  和新的一样了
There you go, good as new.
乖宝宝
Who's a good boy?
捡回来  道格拉维奇先生
Fetch, Mr. Doglavich.
快点干活  鲍勃
Get back to work, Bob.
受死吧
Die!
快点干活  鲍勃
Get back to work, Bob.
快点干活  鲍鲍
Get back to work, Bobby.
天哪
Oh, my God.
琳  我刚刚意识到一件事
Lin, I just realized something.
我的童年太悲催了
I had a bad childhood.
-是的  我知道  -你这是什么意思
- Yeah, I know. - What do you mean you know?
-看看你  -你这又是什么意思
- Look at you. - What do you mean, look at me?
看看你这站姿
Look at how you stand.
童年幸福的人不会这样站着
People who had good childhoods don't stand like that.
记忆中在老爸店里干活挺开心的啊
I thought I remembered having fun working at my dad's place,
可是我却在一直干活
but I was just working...
没完没了地干活
all the time.
依偎着钢丝球
And snuggling with steel wool.
抚摸着肥皂狗
And petting a piece of soap.
说出来感觉好多了
I guess talking about it helps.
孩子们  快点干活
Kids, get back to work.
快点干活  快点干活
Get back to work. Get back to work.
天哪  琳达
Oh, my God! Linda!
孩子们  我和你们老妈想宣布一件事
Kids, your mother and I have an announcement.
又有孩子了  你这岁数还能怀上
You're having another baby? At your age?!
我就觉得你肚子鼓起来了嘛
I knew I spotted a bump.
什么  不  我这是胀气
What?! No, I'm gassy.
不  孩子们  好吧  我要说了
No, guys. Okay, here it goes.
孩子们
Kids...
你们被解雇了
You're fired.
你说神马
Ex-squeeze me?
你们都被解雇了
You're all fired.
是我活该  我总是随波逐流
I deserve this. I've been coasting.
这不是惩罚  这是  这是奖赏
This isn't punishment, it's, it's a gift.
我老爸总是逼我干活
My dad made me work all the time.
-那箱玩具  -糟糕的玩具
- And that box of toys... - Horrible toys.
对  糟糕的玩具
Yes, horrible toys,
让我意识到我从没好好玩过
made me realize that I never had any fun.
所以  我想放你们出去  好好享受暑假
So, I want you to go out and have the summer
还有我不曾拥有过的童年
and the childhood that I never had.
出去吧  出去疯玩
So go out! Go outside!
好好享受童年
Go be children!
可是我们应该玩些什么呢
But what are we supposed to do?
水气球大战
Have a water balloon fight.
空地上玩玩
Play in a vacant lot.
骑车去转转
Ride bikes.
我总是宅在家里
I'm more of an indoor boy.
-不会自卫  也没法招架  -吉恩
- I can't defend myself, I've been declawed. - Gene...
好吧  我们这就出去
All right, well, I guess we're gonna take off.
再会
Arrivedercis.
老爸老妈再见
Bye, mom and dad.
保持联系  别换号码
Keep in touch. Don't change.
秋天见
See you in the fall.
蒂娜  晚上就可以回来了
Tina, you can come home at night.
真高兴你们能把车存在我的车库
I'm glad you kids store your bikes in my garage.
我觉得很有趣
It's fun for me.
有时我假装自己也有三个孩子
Sometimes I pretend I have three kids of my own
假装这些车是他们的
and these are their bikes.
你最喜欢谁
Which kid is your favorite?
承租人
车位
杰里米  他最需要我
Jeremy. He needs me the most.
双胞胎彼此是伴儿
The twins have each other.
有时我来这里  只是想有个牵挂
Sometimes I come in here just so I can trip over 'em.
我会说
I'll be, like,
"孩子们又把车停这儿了"
"The kids left their bikes here again."
好啦  开始享受暑假吧
All right! Summer fun starts now!
纸尿布
Diapers!
招工
如果我...
So, how would you feel about, um...
怎么说好呢
How do I say this... uh...
延期发薪
Deferred payments?
我现在不会发钱  不过...
I wouldn't pay you now, but...
最后一定会的  会有那么一天
Eventually I would, in the future.
接下来的问题不是那么合法
What I'm gonna ask you isn't totally legal.
我不是想和你上床啊...
It's not a sex thing, though, so...
好吧  我看还是把这些简历存起来吧
Okay, I guess I'll keep these resumes on file.
也许我们可以招个不要钱的实习生
Maybe we can get an unpaid intern.
可以让他们去买咖啡
Ooh, they could do coffee runs!
琳  我们店里有咖啡
Lin, we have coffee here.
我不管
I don't care.
还没有人给我买过咖啡呢
No one's ever gotten me coffee!
所有人趴在地上  抢劫
Everybody on the floor! This is a stickup!
米基  你出狱啦
Mickey! Ah, you're out of the slammer.
鲍勃  琳达  过来抱抱
Bob, Linda. Bring it in.
我最爱的人质近来如何呀
How's my favorite hostage?
我记着你被判了八年
I thought you got eight years.
你不是越狱了吧
You didn't escape, did you?
后来大家发现检察官在审讯时磕了药
It turned out the prosecutor was on meth for the entire trial!
他把车开进了孔雀保护区
And he drove his car into a peacock sanctuary.
现在他进去了  我出来了
Now he's in jail and I'm out!
可喜可贺
Oh, good for you.
-我给你拿瓶啤酒  -好啊
- I'll get you a beer. - A beer'd be nice.
你家那几个坏脾气的淘气鬼呢
Hey, where are those whippersnappers of yours, huh?
-被我开除了  -什么  不是吧
- Uh, I fired them. - What? No!
难以接受
That sounds harsh.
我们想让他们好好享受童年
We laid them off to go enjoy themselves.
是啊  比如砸砸窗户
Ah, yeah, sure, breaking windows,
放放火  化化妆
lighting fires, huffing paint,
吸吸胶水
sniffing glue,
工业胶水可以当做毒品吸食
炸炸房子
blowing up houses,
把老鼠塞进瓶子扔进河里...
setting rats in a bottle and throwing them down a river and...
不  不是你想的那样
No, none of those things.
接下来有何打算  米基
So, what's next for you, Mickey?
想做什么
What're you gonna do?
重新做人  鲍勃
Going straight, Bob!
找份工作  泡个妞
Gonna get a job. Find myself a gal or...
不知道现在的人都做些什么
I don't know what people do nowadays.
也许还会盖间车库
Build a barn maybe.
和妞一起给车库刷漆
Paint the barn with the gal.
和妞在车库里...
Put the gal in the barn and...
是啊  不错
Yeah, maybe.
美国梦嘛  美妞加车库
You know, American dream. Gal and a barn.
对嘛  喂  鲍鲍  我说
Yeah. Hey, Bobby, psst.
这是干嘛  我们两个都听得见  琳
What "Psst"? We can both hear you, Lin.
让小基基来嗯哼哼怎么样
What about Ickey-May for the ob-jay?
我肯定他能听懂  琳
I'm pretty sure he can understand you, Lin.
她在说啥
What language is that?
好吧  米基  如果你真想工作的话
Well, Mickey, if you're serious about finding a job,
我们  我们在招暑期工
we-- we need someone for the summer.
我们不会给你太多  亲爱的
We can't pay you that much, honey.
甚至达不到法定标准
Not even what we're legally supposed to.
只要给口饭吃给个床睡就行了
I'd work for meals and a cot in the basement.
我想你可以睡在地下室
Um... I guess you could sleep in the basement.
太好了  好开心哦
Oh, yay! Oh, I love it!
我们又在一起搭档了
We got the team back together again, huh?
-汉堡三剑客  -好耶
- The three amagos. - Ole!
我讨厌夏天
Ugh! Summer is awful.
放松真是一件有压力的事
There's too much pressure to enjoy yourself.
就好像让我们小孩过除夕夜
It's like New Year's Eve for kids.
我们应该回去看一眼
We should probably go by the restaurant.
我敢打赌餐馆没有我们肯定一团糟
I bet that place is falling apart without us by now.
我们种了野燕麦
Well, we've sown our wild oats.
太过瘾了
Things got crazy!
好了  不必哀求  老爸  我们回来了
Anyways, no need to grovel, dad. We're back.
我们都说了言不由衷的话
We all said things we didn't mean.
你说你要炒掉我们  那不是真心的
You said, "You're fired." You did not mean that.
我当时就觉得很假
It sounded very insincere as I remember,
还对自己说  不可能吧
and I thought, "No."
天哪  你们请了别人吗
Oh, my God, is someone here?
你们好呀  小鲍勃们
Hey, Baby Bobs!
孩子们  你们还记得米基吧
Kids, you remember Mickey.
你为了一个银行劫匪把我们炒了
You fired us for a bank robber?
听着  米基  我们回来了
Look, Mickey, we're back now,
快快交出围裙
so you can turn in your apron.
露易丝  不许这样
Louise, no.
你们是我们的孩子  不是员工
You guys are just our kids now, not our employees.
对你来说只是这样吗  老爸
Is that all we are to you, dad?
我们只是你的孩子
Your children?!
没错  我要你们玩个痛快
Yes, and I want you to go have fun.
不要
Never!
别抵抗了  好好玩玩
Stop fighting it and give it a chance!
你不能把我们赶走
You can't make us leave.
不走不走我不走  不走不走我不走
Hell no, I won't go! Hell no, I won't go!
你们怎么比我还有劲儿
Uh! Why are you guys stronger than me?
我们练过普拉提
Pilates!
这是为你们好
This is for your own good!
好  我们骑车去了
Fine! We'll ride our bikes.
骑到很远很远的地方去
Oh, yeah, we'll ride them so far
休想再看到我们
you'll never see us again!
好了  再见了孩子们  玩得开心
Okay, bye, kids. Have fun.
再见  妈妈
Bye, mom.
各位  我们好像迷路了
Guys, I think we're lost.
我知道
I know.
这味道好馋人啊
And all this breathing is making me hungry.
蓝莓树  我们有救了
Blueberry bushes! We're saved!
这是个农场吗  我以为这玩意早就绝迹了呢
Is this a farm? I thought those were extinct.
我们不能偷吃这些蓝莓
We can't just eat these berries.
这农场肯定有主人
They probably belong to someone.
如果你不想别人偷吃你的水果
If you don't want people to eat your fruit,
那就种在保险箱里
grow it inside a safe.
真不知道那些动物是怎么活过来的
I don't know how animals do it.
这玩意好难吃啊  它们肯定也都知道
Fruit is just bad, and they know it.
小宝贝  你们好呀
Hello, children!
-农场主  -他们怎么进来的
- Farmers! - How did those get in there?
别担心  蓝莓我们有的是
Don't worry, we've got plenty of berries.
尽情吃吧
Eat as many as you want.
要来些三明治吗
Or if you'd rather have sandwiches,
我们家里多着呢
we have plenty at the house.
还有蜥蜴哦
And lizards.
我都想吃
I'll eat both.
之后我在林中醒了过来
And then I woke up nude
发现自己裸身骑在马背上
on horseback in the forest,
然后我就看见了她
and there she was,
我的贝芙丽
my Beverly.
我刚刚经过附近的一个畜棚
I had wandered away from a community birthing
那里的牲口正在集体产仔
in a barn nearby.
她看起来像一个正在树下拉粑粑的仙后
She looked like a fairy queene pooping under a tree.
*在树下拉粑粑的仙后*
*A fairy queene pooping under a tree.*
三十年过去了  我们生了五个孩子
Thirty years and five kids later,
现在依旧性致盎然
and we're still doing it.
虽然这个家只剩下我们两个
Well, we've got an empty nest now,
可我们还有这个农场
but we still have our farm.
我们老爸拥有一家餐馆
Our dad has a restaurant.
我们之前在那工作  不过后来被他炒了
We used to work there, but he fired us.
真是可惜
Oh, now, that's a shame.
我们就让孩子在家里工作
We always let our kids work here.
贝芙丽  我有一个好主意
Beverly, I have a crazy idea.
*他们可以在这工作...*
*They could work here...*
在这工作
Work here.
我们付不起太多薪水
We couldn't afford to pay you much.
差不多  一天十块吧
Just, say, ten dollars a day.
一天十块
Ten dollars?!
我可以开始存钱买保时捷卡宴了
I could start saving for my Porsche Cayenne.
可是老爸不想让我们工作啊
But dad doesn't want us to work.
没必要让老爸知道
Dad doesn't have to know.
要不要给他写封信啊
Are we gonna send him a letter?
你想打电话给他吧
You gonna call him up?
-是不是想跟老爸坦白一切啊  -不是
- You gonna find a phone and call dad and tell him stuff? - No.
老爸说过我们可以随心所欲的是吧
Seems like dad told us to just make our way, didn't he?
好吧  我可不想简历上一片空白
Well, I guess I don't want any gaps in my resume.
没错  这就对了
That's right. You don't.
太好了  这儿有很多活你们都能干
Good, because we've got a lot you could do.
比如  除除草[收大麻]
Yes, they could pick the wee...ds.
好主意  贝贝
Great idea, Bev.
这里有好多好多杂草[大麻]
We have a terrible weed problem.
笑点到底在哪
I don't get it!
早上好  孩子们  来点什么
Morning, kids! Can I get you anything?
我就想要你的咖啡
I'll just have your coffee.
-不给  -我就抿一小口
- Give it back. - I'll just have a sip.
露易丝
Louise!
没时间了  露易丝  我们要迟到了
No time, Louise. We're late.
什么要迟到了
Late for what?
这个...那个...
Late to... for our...
有什么可迟到的
What would we be late for?
又不是有班要上
It's not like we have jobs or anything.
我们是去码头
Cause we're late for the pier.
没错  是去码头
Yeah, we gotta go to the pier.
-对  码头  -去码头  玩石头
- Yeah, the pier. - To do our pier, our rock stuff.
玩什么石头
What's rock stuff?
你想问什么
What do you mean...?
-往水里  -对
- Oh, dropping rocks. - Yeah.
扔石头
In the water.
听起来还不错
Sounds fun.
我可以让鱼晕头转向
I can disorient a fish.
了不起
Nice.
你们开心就好
Well, as long as you kids are having fun.
必须的
Oh, yeah.
夏天的石头最好玩了
Summer rocks are the best rocks.
我们该走了
Boy, we should go.
替我扔一个
Well, drop one for me.
我要你的宝贝
I want your nuggets!
你们两个小家伙来挖点东西
You two little critters will be our pickers.
跟我走吧
Now come with me.
吉恩特别擅长挖鼻孔
Gene has tons of experience picking his nose.
还有扣屁眼
And my butt.
蒂娜  你去送蓝莓吧
Tina, you'll be our blueberry delivery girl.
切记  如果被抓到了
Just remember, if you get jammed up,
你不认识我  也不知道这个农场在哪
you don't know my name and you don't know where this farm is.
-我不知道这个农场在哪  -就是这样
- I don't know where this farm is. - Exactly.
米基  一整盘试吃品你都发完了
Wow, Mickey, you handed out the whole tray of samples already?
当然了  鲍勃
Sure did, Bob.
你不介意穿着这身汉堡服吧
And, ah, you don't mind the burger suit?
我喜欢  我喜欢
I love it. I love it.
我知道我在扮演什么  汉堡
I know who I am in this. I'm the burger.
没错  抱歉  这衣服有点紧
Right. Sorry, it's a little tight.
没错  确实紧得要命
It is. It's incredibly snug.
看起来还不错  挺好的
It looks fine. It's good.
我需要你帮我脱掉这身衣服
I'm gonna need your help taking this off, I think.
-可以吗  -当然可以
- If that's all right? - Oh, uh, yeah, sure.
我来看看能不能...
I'll, uh, try and pull the...
不  裤裆那里有几颗扣子
No, you see, there's snaps in the crotch
我胳膊够不着
that my arms aren't long enough to get down to.
你能不能帮忙...解开一下
If you could just... this and that.
我不想碰那里  所以...
Yeah, I don't want to touch down there, so...
可我需要你帮忙  因为我够不到
Well, I need you to, 'cause that's what I can't reach.
只要对准那里  快速解开就行了
If you could root in there real quick and just pop them out.
好吧  那我试试
Okay. Let me just, uh... get in there.
好吧  毛还真多
Yeah, oh, okay, it's hairy, yup.
可以了  谢了  伙计
Ah, there you go. Thanks, man.
米基  你竟然没穿内裤
Whoa, Mickey. You're not wearing any underwear.
坐牢的都不穿内裤
Do not wear underwear in prison.
那玩意可以勒死人
Someone could choke you with it.
你不如就穿着这身汉堡服吧
Well, why don't you leave the burger suit on then, huh?
好吧
All right.
米基真是一个好员工
Hey, Mickey's a pretty good worker, huh?
他是我们雇过的最得力最热情的员工
Yeah. He's the helpful, enthusiastic employee we've never had.
我还是希望他穿上内裤
I wish he'd wear underwear though.
闷骚屁最难斗  哈哈
Yeah, hold the pickle, ha-ha!
杂草就是这么除的
And that's how you pick the weeds!
哪些是杂草啊
Which ones are the weeds?
全部都是
They all are.
杂草为啥长在室内
Why are the weeds inside?
它们不长在室外
So that they aren't outside,
就不会和蓝莓搞混了
messing up the blueberries.
为什么不一把火烧掉这间温室
Why don't you just set this whole greenhouse on fire?
一了百了
Be done with it.
我们打算  一点一点来
Oh, we're going to, one dime at a time.
我给你们唱首干活歌吧
I'll sing you a work song.
*我们干活*
*Well, we work*
*干活  整天干活*
*And we work and we work all day*
*干活  干活  在美国  干活*
*Work, work, work in America, work*
*在草地里干活  美国式工作*
*And we working in the weeds and American work
*在草地里干活  干活干活干活*
*Working in the weeds and a work, work, work
*干活干活干活  来啊  吉恩*
*And worky-work-work, and come on, Gene. *
*跟上拍子  来吧宝贝  一起唱*
*Pick up the pace, come on, buddy, there we go.*
你好  你好
Good day. Hello.
你好
Howdy.
你好  我给你送蓝莓来了
Hi, I have your blueberry delivery.
太好了  新来的蓝莓姑娘
Hey all right, new blueberry girl.
这批货怎么样  很赞吗
How's this batch, pretty kind?
当然  对身体非常好
Yeah, kind to your body.
因为这里有抗氧化成分
Because of antioxidants.
你好  贝尔彻小鬼
Hello, Belcher child.
你爸知道你在做什么吗
Does your father know what you're doing?
-不知道  他以为我在欢度暑假  -很好
- No, he thinks I'm having summer fun. - Good.
-这是我们的秘密  -这是我们的秘密
- Let's keep it that way. - Let's keep it that way.
蓝莓来啦  我正准备去参加烘焙大赛呢
Ooh, blueberries. I'm ready for a bake-off.
蒂娜
Tina?
原来是冰箱啊
Oh, it's just the refrigerator.
你好啊  冰箱
Hey, fridge.
你刚才的声音很像蒂娜
You sure sounded like Tina a second ago.
真想知道她在干嘛
Wonder what she's doing right now.
还有吉恩
And I wonder what Gene's doing.
可能正在放屁
Probably farting.
什么这么好笑
What's so funny?
今日特荐  鲍勃
The burger of the day, Bob.
我刚刚才看到
I just noticed it.
"满足饥渴汉堡/ 问住我了汉堡"
The "Beets Me Burger".
真是太有才了
That's brilliant.
有好几层意思呢
It works on so many levels.
没有那么好啦  我是说...
Well, it's not that good. I mean...
露易丝会想出比这更好的点子
Louise would come up with a better one than that.
比如  她会写
Like, she would write, like,
"糖尿汉堡  内含胰岛素"
"Dia-beets-es Burger, comes with insulin."
这点子不怎么地
Oh... that's in poor taste, huh?
笑点就在这啊
Sure, but that's what makes it fun...
一点也不好笑  好伤人啊
That doesn't sound fun. It sounds hurtful.
这种病很严重的
That's a really terrible disease.
-我知道...  -我祖母就有这病
- Well, I know it is... - My grandmother had that disease.
-对不起  -比比金[美国歌手]也有这病
- Well, I'm sorry. - B.B. King has that disease.
闭嘴  米基
Shut up, Mickey.
抱歉  请别说了
Sorry, but just hush.
我赚了十块钱
Ten dollars in my pocket,
吉恩被蜥蜴咬了
Gene got bitten by a lizard,
梦想成真了  伙计们
we're living the dream, guys.
真希望老爸老妈也在农场工作
I just wish mom and dad worked at the farm with us.
是啊  我好怀念取笑老爸有狐臭
Yeah, I miss making fun of dad's B.O.
我不太敢跟库珀和贝芙丽拿狐臭开玩笑
I'm too scared to make fun of Cooper and Beverly's smell.
我觉得他们一定有问题
I think there's something seriously wrong with them.
蓝莓姑娘
Hey blueberry girl,
你还有多余的蓝莓吗
do you have any extra blueberries on you?
没了  别再来这了  听懂没
No. And don't ever come here again, you hear me?
我父母不知道我在送蓝莓  明白不
My parents don't know I deliver blueberries, get it?
-好了  管他呢  -不行
- Okay, whatever. - No.
你听懂没有
Do you get it?
不  许  再  来
Don't... come... here... again.
好的  再见
Okay, bye.
差点遇到麻烦
That was a close one.
大家都爱吃蓝莓
People love fruit!
我永远也不会明白
I will never understand it.
根本就不好吃
It's not that good.
鲍勃
Bob.
米基又在放《海中女神》了
Mickey's playing his Calypso again.
-你去说说他  -你去
- Can you say something? - You go.
-快去  起来啦  -好吧
- Come on, get up. - All right.
*我帽子上是不是有只小鹦鹉*
*Is that a parakeet in my hat?*
*不不不*
*No, no, no*
*你帽子上的不是小鹦鹉*
*That's not a parakeet in ya hat*
*是不是一只小鳄鱼*
*Is that an alligator*
米基
Mickey?
-我说  米基  -鲍勃
- Hello, Mickey?! - Ha-ho-ho, hey, Bob!
-那是什么  -这个吗
- What's that? - Oh, this?
你没看过这部电影吗  很好看的
Oh, you've never seen this movie? It's great.
是说一个家伙  想要变成巨人
It's a guy, he wants to be big.
然后他变大了  可是他又不想当巨人了
Then he gets big, he doesn't want to be big anymore,
后来又变小了  可是衣服缩不回去了
then he gets small, but the suit's too big.
我在问你海报后面是什么  米基
I'm talking about behind the poster, Mickey.
你在我家墙上挖洞呢吗
Are you making a hole in my wall?
没有没有没有  我在补墙
No, no, no. I was fixing that.
-用镐补墙  -是的
- Fixing it with a pick? - Yes.
-米基  -好吧  鲍勃
- Mickey? - All right, look, Bob.
这话不要告诉别人
Don't tell anybody,
我正在挖一条通往银行的地道
but I'm digging my way to the bank.
什么  不是吧你
What? Come on, no.
这可是一次完美的犯罪
It's the perfect crime.
同一宗罪只能判决一次
我已经有一罪不两审的挡箭牌了
I've got double jeopardy!
你说你一罪不两审是什么意思
What do you mean you have double jeopardy?
鲍勃  我要抢劫上次那家银行
I'm robbing the same bank, Bob.
他们不能以同样的罪名起诉我
They can't try me for it again.
不  他们能的  米基
Yes, they can, Mickey.
听着  记得你当初绑架我的情景吗
Look, remember how you held me hostage?
当然了  笨蛋  我们就是这么认识的嘛
Of course I do, silly. That's how we met.
你也记得当时来了特种部队
And there were SWAT teams,
好多直升飞机和谈判专家吧
and helicopters, and negotiators?
是的  很棒呢  是吧
Yeah, it was great, right?
长点心吧  米基
It wasn't great, Mickey.
我人生中就那么一次
That's the only time in my whole life
希望特种部队能拿枪指着我
I ever want to have SWAT guys pointing guns at my face.
就那么一次
Just that one time.
别再犯事儿了  明白吗
Never again. Got it?
那  我继续挖你不反对吧
So, are you cool with me finishing my tunnel?
不行  不许你从我家打地道到银行
No. You may not tunnel through my basement to a bank.
绝对不行
I forbid it!
好啊  鲍勃  你敢开除我么
Fine, then, Bob, why don't you fire me?
好啊  你被开除了
Okay, you're fired.
你竟然开除我
You're firing me?!
听着  你今晚可以在这过夜
Look, you can stay tonight,
不过明天你必须另谋高就
but tomorrow you're gonna have to find another place.
好吧  好吧
Okay. That's cool.
-镐头我拿走了  -不要
- I'm taking the pick. - No!
鲍勃  我跟你说
Oh, Bob. I tell you.
要想在银行周围50英尺之内找到工作
It's gonna be really tough to find a job
真的很难
within 50 feet of the bank
还让我在地下室蹭床的就更不好找了
that will also let me sleep in the basement.
我肯定你会找到的
Well, I'm sure there's something.
你看我好笨啊
Oh, I'm so clumsy.
快点打扫干净  米基
Better clean that up, Mickey.
其实  我已经开除米基了
Actually, I fired Mickey.
好消息是  我要重新聘用你们
And good news, I'm hiring you all back full time,
马上开始全职工作
starting right now.
那就由你来打扫干净吧
So you can clean it up!
抱歉  老爸  恕难从命
Uh... sorry, dad, but we can't do that.
我知道  我之前说过让你们尽情玩乐的话
Look, I know what I said before about wanting you to have fun,
我本来觉得  我的童年特别苦逼
but the thing is, my childhood was terrible
因为我要一直干活
because I actually had to work,
我老爸从来不说不笑
and my dad never smiled or laughed.
我老爸也是
Yeah, mine neither.
而且他还酗酒
And he had a drinking problem.
我也经历过这些  老兄
Oh, been there, man.
你又使我触景生情了  鲍勃
Open up some fresh wounds here, Bob.
-好了  米基  够了  -好吧
- All right, Mickey, enough. - All right.
我昨天花了一整晚在想这个事情
I spent last night thinking about this,
我是一个好父亲
and I'm a pretty good dad.
是啊  酗酒的人是老妈
Yeah, mom's the one with the drinking problem.
可问题是我压根就不酗酒
The problem is I don't have a frigging drink in my hand!
重点是  你们现在一点也不辛苦
The point is, you guys don't have a hard life, you know?
你们整天就知道瞎闹
You just goof around.
那就在家里闹吧  和我们闹闹
And you should be goofing around here at home, with us.
爸爸  我们已经不计较了
Dad, we've moved on.
-我们有了新的工作  -什么
- We got other jobs. - What?!
我们现在已经是工作女郎了
We're working girls now!
-你是女的  -没错
- You're a girl? - Yes.
-才不是呢  -就是
- Nah. - Yes.
-他不是  -他不是
- He's not. - He's not.
不  这话跟我的阴道说去
No. Tell that to my vagina!
你们有了新的工作
You got other jobs?
有了新的工作  这话什么意思
What do you mean, you got other jobs?
那餐馆怎么办
What about the restaurant?
真是好笑啊  老爸
Oh, that's adorable, dad.
你以为你一打老爸的响指
You thought that you could snap your fancy dad fingers
我们就会乖乖爬回来么
and we'd come crawling back.
你以为你不需要我们  别人也都不需要么
You thought if you didn't want us, nobody else would?
好啊  告诉你吧  库珀和贝芙丽需要我们
Well, guess what, Cooper and Beverly wanted us!
库珀和贝芙丽是谁
Who's Cooper and Beverly?
库珀和贝芙丽
Cooper and Beverly?
他们是农民
They're farmers.
他们的体味很好闻  不用担心这个
And they smell great, so don't even bother asking.
他们还有农场  农场在什么地方
They still have farms? Where do they have farms?
在乡下
Way out in the country
那里的空气非常新鲜
where a man can breathe the air.
抱歉  老爸  希望我们还能做朋友
Sorry, dad. I hope we can still be friends.
等等  他们付多少钱
Wait. Wait. What are they paying you?
我也出一样的价
I'll match it.
一天十块
Ten dollars a day.
那算了  几位走好
Never mind. Have a good day.
拜拜
Bye, guys!
那个戴眼镜的蓝莓姑娘在吗
Hey, is that blueberry delivery girl with the glasses here?
你是说蒂娜  她不在
You mean Tina? She's not here.
我要退掉这些蓝莓
Well, I need to return these blueberries.
你告诉她这里全是梗和籽
Can you tell her they were mostly stems and seeds?
要么给我换盒新的  要么退我40块钱
I want a replacement or my 40 bucks back.
好的  我会告诉她的
Okay, I'll let her know.
-好的  拜拜  -拜拜
- Okay, bye. - Bye.
-真奇怪啊 -40块
- That was weird. - Wow, 40 bucks?
这蓝莓可真贵
Those are expensive blueberries.
大概是有机的吧
They're probably organic.
有股音乐节的味道
Oh, they smell like a music festival.
没错
Huh, you're right.
天啊  琳
Oh, my God, Lin.
他们在大麻地里干活吗
Are the kids working on a pot farm?
那种老式的夹层蓝莓盒
Oh, yeah, the old false-bottom blueberry box.
我小时候就有这种东西
I remember these from when I was a kid.
我们得去找到他们
We have to go get the kids.
可是我们不知道这个大麻农场在哪啊
But we have no idea where this pot farm is.
我知道它在哪
I may have some idea of exactly where it is.
等等  回去  回去  回去  回去
No, wait, go back, go back, go back, go back.
跟我想的不一样嘛
Wow, this isn't what I pictured.
好漂亮啊
It's nice.
我蹲过监狱  老兄
Hey, I've been there, buddy.
你要知道  他们无法囚禁我的大脑
Remember, they can't cage this.
你们在我家地盘上干嘛呢
What are you doing on our property?
来找我们的孩子
We want our kids.
什么孩子  我们这里没有
What kids? There are no kids here.
老爸
Hi, dad.
你们...好呀
Oh, hey... Hello.
你是指我们的孩子吧
Oh, you mean our kids.
你们的  明明是我们的
Your kids? Those are our kids!
孩子们  来  快上车
Come on, guys. Get in the car.
好了  我们走
Now. Let's go.
老妈  老爸  我们已经说过了
Mom, dad, we already explained this.
我们要在这里工作  懂吗
We work here now. Okay?
你们管得有点多了
You're acting a little desperado.
不  露易丝  不许你们再在这里工作
No, Louise, you no longer work here.
老爸  小型农场是美国的支柱产业
Dad, small farms are the backbone of America.
威利・纳尔逊[乡村音乐人]也会爱上这个地方
Willie Nelson would love this place!
没错  他会的  吉恩
Yes, he would, Gene,
不过不是因为你说的那个理由
but not for the reason you're thinking of.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
我不要看见特种部队  我不要看见枪
No SWAT teams! No guns!
红色警报  母亲  红色警报
Code red, mother! Code red!
鲍勃  我该怎么办
Bob, what do I do?
我还没当过无辜的围观群众呢
I've never been an innocent bystander before.
赶紧举手  米基
Just get your hands up, Mickey.
-这样吗  -啥
- Eh, like that? - What?
-不  往上举  -这样吗
- No. Up. - Like this?
你怎么跟小猫似的
The... you're doing like kitty paws.
高点  高点  再高点
Up. Up. Higher.
-高点  这样吗  -不  把胳膊伸直
- Higher? Like that? - No, all the way up.
举过肩膀吗
Like past my shoulders?
趴下  全都趴下
Get down! Everybody down!
我认识这个人
Hey, I know that guy.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
快骑  老爸  快骑
Pedal, daddy, pedal!
右  左  右  左
Right! Left! Right! Left!
右  左  右
Right! Left! Right!
停下
Stop!
右拐右拐
And, uh, oh, let's take a right.
继续骑
Let's keep it moving.
往右  拐弯  再往右
Right, and turning and a little more right.
-快停下  -老天
- Stop, please. - Oh, my God.
在被抓住之前我们赶紧溜吧
We got to get out of here before they catch us.
这样的暑假才过瘾
Whoa! Now this is summer fun!
所以我觉得
And that's why I believe
应该让蓝莓合法化
blueberries should be decriminalized.
我的暑假
露易丝  坐下吧
Louise, sit down.
好了  休息吧  都注意点
Okay, that's recess. Uh, be cool out there.
别抢零食
Don't Bogart the snacks.
如果发生突发事件
And if the po-po rolls up,
第一个要联系的人是律师  不是你妈
your first call's to your lawyer, not your mom.